<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apple | Lumenlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/tag/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-05T17:24:27+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lumenlog.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marcel Langer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.appleoutsider.com/2011/10/06/sj/"/>
		

		<updated>2011-10-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/steve</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Steve

> An era has ended, and we now sit to reflect on our good fortune for having lived in a time when a true giant walked the Earth.

so eloquently says what I have been trying to put into words. We live in a truly amazing time, and some of its awesomeness is Steve's work. He has truly, undeniably changed the world we live in. He also was, and is, an inspiration. I am deeply grateful to have shared a planet with him.

[Jason Kottke](http://kottke.org/11/10/remembering-steve-jobs) has collected some great stories, thoughts and videos on Steve. Do yourself a favor and read some, or at least watch [this video](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8rwsuXHA7RA).

Thank you, Steve. 
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/steve/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Last Rocket]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://shauninman.com/lastrocket/"/>
		

		<updated>2011-08-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/the-last-rocket</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Shaun Inman's brilliant new game, an old-school 8-bit platform puzzler. It looks great, it sounds great and it's quite fun.

It's interesting how there seems to be a market for lo-fi games on iOS. Maybe it's because pixel art looks utterly gorgeous on a high-res display.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/the-last-rocket/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Thibaut Sailly on Our Choice]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://bureau.tsailly.net/2011/05/our-choice.html"/>
		

		<updated>2011-06-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/thibaut-sailly-on-our-choice</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Kudos for writing the review I was to lazy to write. Apart from that, I also like his opening statement on eBooks in general:

> Because of these lacks in function and emotions, I tend to perceive eBooks as a convenience: you can buy them from your couch, they have no weight, and they don't age. You give away all the sexyness, presence and reliability of a nice paper book for accessibility and zero impact on your bookshelf.

That's kind of sad, but also true.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/thibaut-sailly-on-our-choice/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone Tracker]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://petewarden.github.com/iPhoneTracker/"/>
		

		<updated>2011-04-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/iphone-tracker</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[<p>Das iPhone hebt schön brav alle GPS-Koordinaten auf, die es jemals hatte. Dieses Programm zeigt sie an. Ja. Eh. Post-privacy.</p>
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/iphone-tracker/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[iTunes & OCD]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://hessi.tumblr.com/post/1073937480/using-itunes-part-1-introduction-to-stars"/>
		

		<updated>2010-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/itunes-ocd</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Hessi von Bits und so erklärt, wie man mit iTunes komplexere Systeme zur Verwaltung von Musik erstellt. Eines der Ziele ist es, immer automatisch Musik vorgespielt zu bekommen, die man mag und länger nicht gehört hat. Und nach Sternen aufgeschlüsselte Playlists zu erstellen. Und Playlisten eine bestimme Größe für die Synchronisierung zuzuweisen. Und... Bis jetzt sind zwei Teile verfügbar, aber es werden wohl noch einige folgen. (Teil: <a href="http://hessi.tumblr.com/post/1073937480/using-itunes-part-1-introduction-to-stars">1</a>, <a href="http://hessi.tumblr.com/post/1081964615/using-itunes-part-2-quarantine-periods">2</a>)
<span class="en">A power-user's guide to iTunes on how to create an <strike>OCD</strike> <strike>anal</strike> complex system for dealing with music. Worth a read. There are two parts already available, but I believe there will be many more... (Part: <a href="http://hessi.tumblr.com/post/1073937480/using-itunes-part-1-introduction-to-stars">1</a>,<a href="http://hessi.tumblr.com/post/1081964615/using-itunes-part-2-quarantine-periods">2</a>)</span>
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/itunes-ocd/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
</feed>
