<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iPad | Lumenlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/tag/ipad/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-05T17:24:27+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lumenlog.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marcel Langer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Last Rocket]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://shauninman.com/lastrocket/"/>
		

		<updated>2011-08-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/the-last-rocket</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Shaun Inman's brilliant new game, an old-school 8-bit platform puzzler. It looks great, it sounds great and it's quite fun.

It's interesting how there seems to be a market for lo-fi games on iOS. Maybe it's because pixel art looks utterly gorgeous on a high-res display.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/the-last-rocket/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Thibaut Sailly on Our Choice]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://bureau.tsailly.net/2011/05/our-choice.html"/>
		

		<updated>2011-06-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/thibaut-sailly-on-our-choice</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Kudos for writing the review I was to lazy to write. Apart from that, I also like his opening statement on eBooks in general:

> Because of these lacks in function and emotions, I tend to perceive eBooks as a convenience: you can buy them from your couch, they have no weight, and they don't age. You give away all the sexyness, presence and reliability of a nice paper book for accessibility and zero impact on your bookshelf.

That's kind of sad, but also true.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/thibaut-sailly-on-our-choice/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Choice]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://pushpoppress.com/ourchoice/"/>
		

		<updated>2011-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/our-choice</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Das erste "Multimedia-Buch" das mir wirklich gut gefällt. Ich bin gerade erst mit dem zweiten Kapitel fertig, aber beeindruckt von der Qualität des Interaktionsdesigns, der Typographie, den Bildern und dem Konzept. Inhalt? Interessant, bis jetzt wenig wirklich neues, aber gut und eindringlich formuliert.
<span class="en">The first interactive, multi-media book that I like. The interaction design is stunningly well done, the typography is more than bearable, the combination of text, pictures, videos and infographics works and above all, it's actually fun to read. The content? Good so far, nothing particularly new. The subject is as important as ever.</span>
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/our-choice/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Fry über das iPad]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.time.com/time/business/article/0,8599,1976935-1,00.html"/>
		

		<updated>2010-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/stephen-fry-uber-das-ipad-2</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Dieser (zensiert) durfte ins Hauptquartier fahren, mit Steve Jobs reden und ein iPad ausprobieren. Der Artikel ist großartig.
<span class="en">I'm so jealous. He got to try an iPad and talk to Steve. The article is great, by the way.</span>
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/stephen-fry-uber-das-ipad-2/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Magazine auf dem iPad]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://berglondon.com/blog/2010/04/02/popularscienceplus/"/>
		

		<updated>2010-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/magazine-auf-dem-ipad</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[So ein Magazin würde ich kaufen, obwohl ich auch dem altmodischen Papier etwas abgewinnen kann. Außerdem erspart es uns die absurd hohen Preise für ausländische Zeitungen. Digitale Inhalte muss man eben nicht ins Flugzeug laden.
<span class="en">Even though I really like paper, this looks like a great alternative, especially for us Germans. Digital content is independent from location, so it saves us the ridiculous shipping fees. In Germany, an issue of Wired UK is 10€. Absurd. (At least the subscriptions are almost reasonably priced.)</class>
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/magazine-auf-dem-ipad/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
</feed>
