<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Internet | Lumenlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/tag/internet/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-05T17:24:27+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lumenlog.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marcel Langer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Fish: A Tap Essay]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.robinsloan.com/fish/"/>
		

		<updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/fish-a-tap-essay</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Everything about this essay by Robin Sloan is brilliant: The writing, the presentation, and the marketing.

**Writing**: "Fish" is a short, but thought-provoking essay on the relationship between liking and loving content on the web. Robin makes some great points on how to deal with the onslaught of interesting *stuff* the web keeps throwing at us. Definitely worth your time, and probably very suitable to being re-read from time to time.

**Presentation**: This is the fun part. This essay was not published on a blog, but in form of a little iPhone app. Even though I think that this shouldn't become a standard, I'll let this one pass. Because it's so damn beautiful and fun. It feels more like watching the slides of a talk than reading an essay. There are a few lines of text at most on every screen, sometimes just a word. And at some point, oddly enough, the picture of a fish. 

**Marketing**: The idea is slightly evil, but still brilliant: The most memorable lines of this essay have a Twitter button built right in. A few taps and you can tweet it, including a link to the essay, of course. Instant marketing, done in style. (You should totally found a company with that motto.)
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/fish-a-tap-essay/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t Fear the Internet]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.dontfeartheinternet.com/"/>
		

		<updated>2011-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/don%e2%80%99t-fear-the-internet</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[A beautifully designed website created in order to teach everyone the basic building blocks of the web. What an utterly great idea.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/don%25e2%2580%2599t-fear-the-internet/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stop Worrying and Learn to Love the Internet]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.douglasadams.com/dna/19990901-00-a.html"/>
		

		<updated>2011-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/how-to-stop-worrying-and-learn-to-love-the-internet-2</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[About ten years ago, one of the smartest, most brilliant writers I know died, leaving behind words that make me smile, think and just bow with respect for utter genius. This essay has been linked to quite a bit in the last few days, mostly because it so accurately describes the media's attitude towards the Internet. He wrote that in 1999, and (sadly) it's still true.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/how-to-stop-worrying-and-learn-to-love-the-internet-2/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stop Worrying and Learn to Love the Internet]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.douglasadams.com/dna/19990901-00-a.html"/>
		

		<updated>2010-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/how-to-stop-worrying-and-learn-to-love-the-internet</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[<blockquote>We are natural villagers. For most of mankind’s history we have lived in very small communities in which we knew everybody and everybody knew us. But gradually there grew to be far too many of us, and our communities became too large and disparate for us to be able to feel a part of them, and our technologies were unequal to the task of drawing us together. But that is changing.</blockquote>

Douglas Adams. Ein Artikel von 1999, und immer noch so wahr.
<span class="en">Ah, Douglas Adams. Solid gold, even though the piece is from 1999.</wn>
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/how-to-stop-worrying-and-learn-to-love-the-internet/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
</feed>
