<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Links | Lumenlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/tag/links/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lumenlog.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-05T17:24:27+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lumenlog.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marcel Langer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Richard Feynman: No Ordinary Genius]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fzg1CU8t9nw"/>
		

		<updated>2012-04-03T23:28:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/richard-feynman-no-ordinary-genius</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[What a coincidence, I just started reading "Sureley You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!", and then this great 90-minute documentary about him pops up on Kottke. I guess I will come back to this every time I doubt that I picked the right subject to study.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/richard-feynman-no-ordinary-genius/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Some more Sloan: Annabel Scheme &amp; Mr. Penumbra’s 24-Hour Bookstore]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.robinsloan.com/annabel-scheme/"/>
		

		<updated>2012-04-03T17:37:00+02:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/some-more-sloan-annabel-scheme-and-mr-penumbras-24-hour-bookstore</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[> “She’s wearing the same red-and-yellow BAM! t-shirt as yesterday, which means a) she slept in it, b) she owns several identical t-shirts, or c) she’s a cartoon character—all of which are appealing alternatives.”

To continue the Sloan love fest: You should totally read this novella too. It gets slightly weird towards the end, but the first half is a sweet Gibsonesque near-future detective story with some genuinely amazing ideas thrown in.

Also, this short story: [Mr. Penumbra’s 24-Hour Bookstore](http://robinsloan.com/mr-penumbra/). Also has a strange ending, but the first 75% are pure awesome. Go make yourself a hot beverage of your liking, put on some nice music, and read for a bit.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/some-more-sloan-annabel-scheme-and-mr-penumbras-24-hour-bookstore/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Fish: A Tap Essay]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://www.robinsloan.com/fish/"/>
		

		<updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/fish-a-tap-essay</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Everything about this essay by Robin Sloan is brilliant: The writing, the presentation, and the marketing.

**Writing**: "Fish" is a short, but thought-provoking essay on the relationship between liking and loving content on the web. Robin makes some great points on how to deal with the onslaught of interesting *stuff* the web keeps throwing at us. Definitely worth your time, and probably very suitable to being re-read from time to time.

**Presentation**: This is the fun part. This essay was not published on a blog, but in form of a little iPhone app. Even though I think that this shouldn't become a standard, I'll let this one pass. Because it's so damn beautiful and fun. It feels more like watching the slides of a talk than reading an essay. There are a few lines of text at most on every screen, sometimes just a word. And at some point, oddly enough, the picture of a fish. 

**Marketing**: The idea is slightly evil, but still brilliant: The most memorable lines of this essay have a Twitter button built right in. A few taps and you can tweet it, including a link to the essay, of course. Instant marketing, done in style. (You should totally found a company with that motto.)
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/fish-a-tap-essay/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[one tiny hand]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://onetinyhand.com/"/>
		

		<updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/one-tiny-hand</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[Best. Tumblr. Ever. I honestly laughed out loud when I saw the first picture, and just kept on laughing until I reached the end.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/one-tiny-hand/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
  <entry>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Wars: Machete Order]]></title>
		
			<link href="http://static.nomachetejuggling.com/machete_order.html"/>
		

		<updated>2012-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://lumenlog.com//post/star-wars-machete-order</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[The nerdiest and probably best thing you're going to read today: An alternative order to watch all the Star Wars movies. Well, except episode I, which is left out of this order because it is kind of crappy. It's very well-argued too, and entirely readable just for the assorted Star Wars nerdery.

I so totally adore this idea. Now I just need to find some time to re-watch all of the movies. Again. In the right order this time.
]]>
			
				<![CDATA[<a class="permalink" href="http://lumenlog.com/post/star-wars-machete-order/">Permalink</a>]]>
			
		</content>
	</entry>
  
</feed>
